It's all fun and games until someone raises the dead.
ParaNorman is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Sam Fell.
In the town of Blithe Hollow, Norman Babcock can speak to the dead, but no one
other than his eccentric new friend believes his ability is real.
One day, Norman's eccentric uncle tells him of a ritual he must perform to
protect the town from a curse cast by a witch centuries ago.
Norman Babcock (voice), played by Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Neil Downe (voice), played by Tucker Albrizzi.
Courtney Babcock (voice), played by Anna Kendrick.
Mitch Downe (voice), played by Casey Affleck.
Alvin (voice), played by Christopher Mintz-Plasse.
Sandra Babcock (voice), played by Leslie Mann.
ParaNorman is a 2012 American stop motion animated comedy horror film
directed by Sam Fell and Chris Butler, and written by Butler.
Produced by Laika, the film stars the voices of Kodi Smit-McPhee, Jodelle Ferland, Bernard Hill, Tucker Albrizzi, Anna Kendrick, Casey
Affleck, Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Leslie Mann, Jeff Garlin, Elaine Stritch,  Tempestt Bledsoe, Alex Borstein, and John Goodman.
It is the first stop-motion film to use a 3-D color
printer to create character faces.
In the film, Norman Babcock, a young boy who can communicate with ghosts, is given the
task of ending a 300-year-old witch's curse on his Massachusetts town.
The idea of ParaNorman came from Butler, who thought making such a movie for kids could help express the challenges
kids face growing up, after realizing that zombie films often contained a degree of social commentary.
Production of the stop-motion animation took place at Laika's studio in Hillsboro, Oregon for three years,
with the animating stage of production lasting about two years and beginning in late 2009.
Instead of using traditional 3-D format cameras, the studio had
sixty Canon EOS 5D Mark II DSLR cameras film the movie.
Jon Brion composed the film's musical score.
ParaNorman was released on August 17, 2012, by Focus Features.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its animation and script, and was
a modest box office success, earning $107 million against a budget of $60 million.
The film was nominated for an Academy Award and a BAFTA for Best Animated Film.
The film explores themes of medium, jock, stop motion, curse, zombie.
The tone is lighthearted.